Where's the equipment?
Kurva!
What happened?
Caught on one of the branches
on the way down.
Can you walk?
You'll need stitches.
Hey.
You didn't hide your parachutes very well,
and you left a blood trail
for half a kilometer.
Follow me.
I live not far from here.
Dik! Come!
Ignác.
Ignác!
Hot soup. Come.
Come in.
I take it you are heading for Prague.
How far is it?
Thirty kilometers.
I have a special
delivery permit for my truck.
I could take you.
Thank you.
You rest here tonight.
I will take you in the morning.
Enjoy your soup.
Please, sit.
How much do the Germans pay you?
For turning in
your fellow countrymen, huh?
Drop the gun.
I said, drop the gun.
Drop it.
Drop the gun!
Gun.
You get him?
We'll take that truck.
Come on.
They had made their choice, Jan.
Sometimes you have to pick a side.
Would you prefer it was us?
Should be the next left.
Pull over here.
Mirek, come away from the window.
Anna, get the door!
Yes?
We are looking for Oldrich Novák.
The Novákovi no longer live here.
Who is it?
Just somebody looking for directions.
I am sorry, but that's all I know.
Please.
Can you help us?
There is a veterinarian in the next row
of shops up the street.
I hear he is a good man.
One that may help.
Thank you.
He normally only barks at Germans.
Mmm-mmm. Germans and anyone
giving him a rectal examination.
Thank you, Dr. Eduard.
Come along, Benés.
Look after him, Mrs. Lukešová.
Normally, for a dog bite,
you would go to a hospital, not a vet.
Did you know Oldrich Novák?
Yes.
And what if we were to say that Oldrich
Novák was our contact here in Prague?
Then I would have to wonder
if you are ill-informed Czech patriots
or Gestapo spies trying to infiltrate
what remains of the resistance.
I don't detect a German accent.
The decoding papers in your bag,
they don't have a German font.
And given that this wound
has more tree bark than dog bite,
I would have to guess that you were
parachuted back into Czechoslovakia
with information that
was somewhat out of date.
You're a clever man.
We were also told you were a good man.
How long have you been away?
It's been a while.
Rewards are given to people
who inform on anti-Nazi activity.
Heydrich has all but crushed
the resistance.
He has executed thousands.
I can put you in contact with the miller.
Maybe he can help you.
You can stay here tonight.
I'll contact the miller in the morning.
My friend here says
that you are a clever man.
I agree.
Don't do anything that
would change our opinion.
Go easy on the foot.
You will be dancing
the tango within a week.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
This is Břetislav.
The miller.
Eduard told me you were
looking for Oldrich Novák.
Yes.
Would you like to take a drive with me?
Don't move.
Please sit.
You were looking for Oldrich Novák.
Who gave you this contact?
London.
And you tell us this because?
You are not giving us much choice and
this doesn't look like Gestapo headquarters.
You, where are you from?
Your accent, Bohemia?
No, Dolní Vilémovice, Moravia.
So you must know the railway
station at Vladislav?
Yes.
What's so special about it?
I presume you are talking about
the large bed of colored roses
that when seen from above
is in the shape of our national flag?
Is it still there?
Seems the Germans have still
not looked at it from above.
I am Vanek.
Ladislav Vanek.
This is Uncle Hajsky.
We are the head
of the Jindra Organization.
Czech resistance.
I am Jan Kubiš.
I am Josef Gabčík.
From Slovakia.
You must not be surprised
by our lack of trust.
The Gestapo have been very successful
in infiltrating our network.
Oldrich Novák.
He was taken away several months ago.
Why wasn't London informed?
We lost contact with the Czech government
in exile in London some months ago.
We need replacement crystals
for the transmitter.
We've been waiting for them to send
someone to re-establish contact.
Is that you?
There were other men on the plane.
They were dropped elsewhere.
It's possible they have orders
to re-establish contact
with London but that...
That is not our mission.
What is your mission?
Operation Anthropoid.
Anthropoid?
What is Anthropoid?
We are here to assassinate
SS Obergruppenfűhrer Reinhard Heydrich.
Are you completely mad?
- We have our orders, comrade.
- But this is madness.
We have our orders, comrade.
Heydrich?
Why stop with Heydrich?
Why not have a go at Hitler as well?
He is only 300 kilometers down the road
in a small village called Berlin.
So we inform London that you are
refusing to cooperate with our mission.
How dare you question us?
You know what we have
sacrificed for the cause here?
What you have sacrificed?
What has Czechoslovakia sacrificed?
You have no idea what we've sacrificed!
Sit down. Please.
You kill Heydrich and Hitler
will tear Prague apart.
I take it you have family
in Czechoslovakia?
Father? Mother?
You kill Heydrich, then you can consider them
and everyone that ever knew you dead.
All Czech patriots should be
ready to die for their country.
That includes my family.
Well, I'm not.
I want to carry on fighting.
We don't have that many left
that are willing to do that.
We are what's left
of the Czech resistance.
I suggest a lesser rank
should be assassinated.
Perhaps a few of them.
Heydrich is the head of the secret police.
Only Hitler and Himmler are
above him in the Nazi hierarchy.
Exactly my point.
You really think you'll ever get close
enough to assassinate Heydrich?
Our orders have come direct
from the Czech government in London.
So this is about the Czech government
in London trying to impress the allies?
It was the allies that gave us
to the Germans in the first place.
Munich was a betrayal,
but it is also now history.
I think what the Czech government
in London is asking is this.
Is Czechoslovakia
still ready and willing
to resist Nazi Germany?
Josef Gabčík.
And Jan Kubiš.
You are both most welcome here.
And please call me Auntie Moravec.
Ata. Ata.
Ata is my son.
He is studying to be a violinist.
Ata, this is Josef and this is Jan.
Pleased to meet you both.
So, try not to go outside,
but if you do, never walk together.
If you're stopped, you will need
an excuse for why you're not at work.
We'll try to get you medical
certificates as soon as possible.
Always use our code,
three knocks, then a single knock.
In the meantime,
lay low and I will use
Ata to make contact.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Come on through, please.
Josef.
There is a way off the roof?
There is a fire escape to the left.
To the right it continues
to the building next door.
It's good enough.
I'm sure you both would
like a glass of Becherovka.
Thank you.
- It's okay.
- Mrs. Moravec?
- Hey.
There was so much people at the market.
But I didn't find the bread that you like.
Come.
- Who is it?
- It's okay, Marie.
This is Josef and this is Jan.
They will be staying with us
while they are looking for work.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Hello.
Josef and Jan are not
registered with the police
as being residents here, so, remember,
please keep it strictly to yourself.
I'll put the shopping in the kitchen.
Welcome.
Mrs. Kovárníková's daughter.
I pay her for helping out.
Dinner will be at 6:00.
Please sit.
Ata, dinner is ready.
And finally the fiddler is silent.
He is a violinist, Alois. A violinist.
You two boys looking for work, then?
Yes.
We are always looking for men to clean
the cinders out of the locomotives.
Thank you, Mr. Moravec.
We'll keep that in mind.
So, what do you do when you
aren't helping out here?
You don't have a boyfriend?
No.
How's life in occupied Prague, Marie?
I guess, not being registered
with the police as residents
has something to do with this question?
I hate the Germans.
And tell me, do you have a friend
as lovely as you that...
That you can trust?
Why?
It would be less conspicuous if Jan
and I were not seen out alone.
Young love flourishes
under German occupation.
That sort of thing.
But you're not that young.
Knowing that you are trustworthy
is one thing, Marie.
But doing this could get you shot.
Perhaps you should think about it...
My friend, Lenka.
She sometimes carries
messages for Uncle Hajsky.
Good.
We are going to a New Year's Eve
dance tomorrow night.
Would you like to go?
Look at them.
It's like...
It's like some old ritual
that's lost its joy.
Maybe there's hope in the pretense.
Hello.
It looks like you've landed
on your feet with Lenka.
This was a mistake.
Hello.
Lenka, this is Jan and Josef.
- You know, it's not very polite...
- Please sit down.
You are the most
beautiful women in the room.
Congratulations.
But you fail to understand this is...
This is not a night off for us.
This is not some game.
Josef, maybe you're
overreacting a little...
Jan, take a look around.
We appreciate the effort, but the point
was not to attract attention.
We needed you as plain as possible.
Do you understand?
You know, for most girls,
a little lipstick is the only way
to forget what's happening here.
Even if it's just for a few hours.
Yes.
Your lipstick gets you noticed,
and that gets us noticed,
and us being noticed gets us all shot.
This little scene needs an ending.
Slap my face.
I'm not a whore.
I think that went well.
Nine... Eight... Seven...
Six... Five... Four...
Three... Two... One.
A British Sten Mark II machine gun.
One hundred rounds.
And Model 73 anti-tank
grenades with pencil fuses.
That's everything we could retrieve
from the drop canister.
Uncle says he has made some progress
with the information you asked for.
There is a meeting at Café Moravia
on Vodičkova Street.
Tuesday. 2:00.
I just wanted to apologize
about the other night.
You were completely right
to do what you did.
Marie didn't fully inform me
about the situation.
She is very young,
she still has romantic ideas
about the war.
And you?
War is not romantic.
We cross here.
After our last date, I thought you
might both show wearing potato sacks.
I don't know what I'm doing.
You are doing fine.
Take a seat here. Order a drink.
We won't be long.
Josef.
- Jan.
- Opálka.
Valčík.
I see you are no strangers to one another,
but we don't have much time.
We all trained special
operations together.
Valčík here was even on the same drop.
Yes, dropped 10 minutes later
and 30 miles off course.
Thanks to Valčík and his group Silver A,
we have finally re-established
communications with London.
I have orders to send and receive any
communications between you and London.
You have your own decoder book, right?
Yes.
Second Lieutenant Opálka
and Warrant Officer Curda
have completed Operation Out Distance,
so both are now available to assist you.
Second Lieutenant Opálka
is the senior officer here.
Yes, this is true, but your mission
objective supersedes my rank.
We had word from London. Anthropoid.
Utmost priority.
We assist with everything possible.
So...
This is your show, bratři.
So, we know that Heydrich
returns to his family
every day at Panenské Břežany.
But, both his chateau and the castle
are both heavily guarded.
They are not feasible targets.
But once a month,
he also travels to Berlin, by train.
And we can predict this
because his personal carriages
are prepared several days in advance.
But, again, the station and the train
are both heavily guarded.
What about derailing
the train outside of Prague?
We can derail the train, but that is
no guarantee that Heydrich is killed.
I have made contact
with an ex-pupil of mine
who works as a repair man
inside the castle.
He's willing to help,
but he only knows when Heydrich
arrives in the morning
and when he leaves.
What good is that?
You can build a picture
of his routine.
Sometimes he travels with an armed
escort and sometimes he does not.
Perhaps there is a pattern in this.
There is a safe house near the castle.
The repairman could drop off
the timetable every day before work.
Lenka or Marie could collect it.
Good.
And Jan and I will follow the route
from the chateau to the castle.
Gentlemen, this operation
will involve almost everyone
we have left in the resistance.
So many have been captured by the Gestapo.
If you are arrested,
you will face some harsh facts.
There will be no escape.
You'll be tortured until you reveal
everything you know,
and then you will be executed.
You must protect your fellow comrades
by shutting down
any links you have to them.
Operation Out Distance
has re-supplied us with these.
Carry the cyanide capsules at all times.
We have to end our meeting.
Use the window.
Clear.
Looks like there's a whole garrison there.
That's our man.
Five minutes after 9:00.
He's riding solo today.
Wait.
Armed escort.
Thirty seconds behind.
Thirty seconds.
Thirty seconds, 30 seconds.
If we can use a rope
or a steel cable to stop the Mercedes,
then 30 seconds...
Then 30 seconds would be all we need.
Even if a rope can stop the car,
we still need more than 30 seconds
to escape from here.
And we'd have to face the
armed guard here in the open.
It would not be my first choice.
And if it's our only choice?
The point of the mission
is to succeed. Yes?
I'm more worried that we haven't planned
what to do if we are successful.
What happens afterwards is not important.
Let's follow the route to the castle.
Well?
Arrived 9:15, left 5:15,
with an armed escort.
Armed escort?
There's only one person in Prague
that travels with an armed escort.
Are you going to assassinate Heydrich?
What?
Heydrich is the target?
For your own safety, it's best that
you don't ask too many questions.
It's a bit too late for that now.
Well, you agreed to help the resistance.
Who the target is should not concern you.
We are about to help you
assassinate Reinhard Heydrich.
- Of course it concerns us.
- Okay.
Everyone just relax.
Maybe it was a mistake
not to inform you of the danger.
- Murder Heydrich?
- No, no.
Assassinate Heydrich.
Murder implies he has a life worth living.
So you think we are just two little girls
who are here to follow the important
parachutists around?
Whoa. Lenka.
We've been resisting here
from the beginning in our own way.
I personally don't have any
reservation to killing a Nazi pig.
But don't treat us like what you are
about to do doesn't affect us.
It does and it will.
And you should keep your weapon
clean because it's filthy.
Marie?
Where are all my pots and pans?
This exit here, is this.
You see?
It's the slowest part of the route.
Anywhere else is impossible.
So we do it here.
Agreed?
Yes.
Perhaps not perfect,
but it's the best option.
Good.
9:17 to 4:41.
Without.
Are you really going
to go through with this?
We have our orders.
So, you kill Heydrich.
What then?
You think there aren't more like him?
They come and the killing continues
even worse than it did before.
When does it stop?
I wish I had an answer for you.
You think any of this makes sense to me?
Then walk away now.
And go where, Marie?
You think we can escape
from what is happening here?
Pretend this madness is not real?
Some days I'm not even sure it is real.
Heydrich chokes the people
of this city with a blanket of fear.
People are shot for what?
Their race? Their religion?
Their cigarettes?
You hear the stories about Poland.
Marie, it's okay.
Just tell me we are doing the right thing.
I think it is my turn to apologize
to you about the other morning.
You were right to be angry.
We should have told you what was at risk.
Given you the choice to walk away.
My father was a captain in the army.
Wanted sons, got three daughters.
He and many others were arrested in '39
when Germany took control
over Czechoslovakia.
And when Heydrich took
over here last September,
his first order was to
execute all the prisoners.
My father was among 5,000 shot
in the first week by Heydrich.
For me there's no walking away.
Heydrich is worth the risk.
We have checked the route.
We think we know how to do it.
I will arrange a meeting.
At the cafe, the day after tomorrow.
3:00 p.m.
Our original contact, Oldrich Novák.
Who was his direct handler?
Ladislav Vanek.
He is the one who's most opposed
to what we have to do.
All I'm asking is what is he so afraid of?
Jan?
Sorry.
So he approaches here.
Corner of Kirchmayer
and Holeschowitzer Street.
Here.
Yes, his car will have to really
slow down to take that corner.
Yes, he slows to about 10 miles per hour.
We've averaged out
his morning arrival times.
We can expect him
at approximately 9:30 a.m.
And the weapons?
At that range the Sten gun should hit
everything within the car.
And the armed escort?
We have found no pattern.
Some days, yes. Some days, no.
If there is an armed escort,
we stand down and await the next day.
You know I have been against
this action from the start.
Yes, that's been clear.
I cannot give the go-ahead
without asking London to reconsider.
Ladislav, this is a military operation.
It's not your order to give...
Without the resistance,
this mission doesn't exist.
Do you want to put...
I am with Ladislav.
We should get London to rethink
our position here in Prague.
We have our orders, Curda.
And nothing has changed.
It's easy for London to give orders.
It's our lives on the line...
Let's wait for re-confirmation.
We waited four months.
Four months.
London needs action.
Then a few more days
won't make a difference.
Valčík, how long before you
can get to the transmitter?
I can get to the transmitter
the day after tomorrow.
Then a couple of days for London
to transmit back the answer.
Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday, Ata.
- Thank you.
- Cheers.
Cheers.
- It's beautiful.
- Thank you.
Uh...
Ata, I know this is your party,
but we have a little announcement to make.
I have asked Marie to marry me
and she has said yes.
Congratulations.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Congratulations.
Why are we here?
Hmm?
I know.
Who's to say it won't happen?
London calls it off.
You're lying to yourself, my friend.
Because it is easier.
I have to believe
there is a way through this.
That there is a normal life
waiting for us.
The way things used to be.
Marie makes me feel that there is hope.
I love her.
I do. I love her.
I had the idea to transfer the 73
into a water canteen for better mobility.
Rigged for impact detonation.
Don't drop them, eh?
That was the empty one.
No, not funny, Jan.
Not funny.
"Anthropoid proceed.
"Stop.
"Upmost importance."
Nothing about getting us out afterwards.
There's a problem.
One of our contacts inside
the castle has seen correspondence
ordering Heydrich back to Berlin.
And there have been
conversations in the household
about a new posting to Paris.
It means that once he goes
to Berlin, he may not be back.
When does he leave?
Day after tomorrow.
Then we have no choice.
We do it tomorrow.
What? What is it?
Ladislav has received
a new transmission from London.
And?
They agreed with my request
to stand down the mission.
We believe we see the situation clearly,
therefore, given the situation,
any actions against officials
of the German Reich
do not come into consideration.
Let the Jindra group know.
No.
Ladislav,
I've just decoded a message from London.
"Proceed. Upmost importance."
But this clearly states
you must stand down.
You are deluded. This is for Jindra.
So how can we recognize this?
Then at least wait for us to clarify it.
It may have superseded your order.
We have no time.
After tomorrow Heydrich will be gone.
I agree with Josef.
I don't think this is a direct command.
I believe its purpose
is to calm the nerves in Jindra.
I know you all doubt me.
- No, Ladislav...
- Please stop.
Suspect me of collaboration.
I know you've had me followed.
I understand you don't trust me, but,
if I was an informer for the Gestapo,
do you think you would still be here?
Do you?
Then you tell me, Ladislav.
What are you afraid of?
I fear Czechoslovakia
will be wiped from the map.
You ask me if I'm afraid?
Yes, I'm afraid.
Jan, Uncle, we do it tomorrow.
As planned.
May God be with you.
Jan.
I've shot at men in the field.
Never killed one up close.
Give me the gun. Give me the gun.
- I don't want to die tomorrow.
- Give me the gun.
Breathe. Breathe.
Now...
Thank you, Mrs. Moravec. Thank you.
Okay. Breathe. Breathe.
Breathe. Breathe, Jan.
Good.
Now, as we were trained.
As we were trained.
Concentrate on the detail.
Good.
We are not afraid.
Jan, we are not afraid.
Czechoslovakia is not afraid.
Huh?
I will wait for you up the street.
Uncle said we weren't needed for a while.
Is it today?
Promise me.
We have plenty of time.
8:25.
Where's Curda?
Never mind.
Valčík, you take this street behind me.
We have some sun, so take this.
If he approaches without an armed escort,
then use it to signal.
And if he does?
Then... Then light a cigarette.
When the car slows to take the corner,
I will step out and open fire
with the Sten gun.
This will signal the attack.
Jan, you stand behind the attack point
so you can throw grenades
at the armed escort if there is one.
Opálka, you try a slow walk across here.
As he approaches, maybe you can
slow him down before he takes the corner.
Is that clear?
Yeah.
Good luck.
- All good?
- Good.
As we were trained.
Let's move!
Stop!
Where were you, Curda?
I didn't think that you
were really going to do it.
It's all over the radio. You shot him?
The radio said 20,000 SS troops
have been drafted in to look for us.
I need to get my family out of Prague.
No, Curda.
No one is going anywhere, Curda.
You try and run now and they will
pick you up before you reach the city limits.
You go home to your family,
you stay calm, you shut your mouth.
- You think you can do that? Huh?
- Yeah.
- We failed, Curda.
- Failed? No.
We failed.
Jan?
Jan.
The Sten...
I'm sorry.
Karl Frank has temporarily
taken Heydrich's place,
and has proclaimed a state
of emergency and a curfew.
A reward of 10 million crowns
will be given for any information
that leads to the arrest of the criminals.
Anyone caught aiding the criminals
will be shot,
along with his entire family.
What went wrong out there?
We didn't even kill him.
Wounded.
How bad?
It's hard to say.
The SS still have the hospital surrounded,
so presumably, he's still alive.
It seems like the Germans have
more men and guns up there
than on the Eastern Front.
They have taken several thousand hostages.
So, what do we do now?
Nothing is leaving or entering Prague.
They are searching door to door.
We have no safe houses left.
So, where do we go?
I've asked Father Vladimir Petrek.
He has agreed to hide
all the parachutists
that are still here in Prague
until we can return you to London.
Wait here, a few hours.
I will find a safe route to the cathedral.
Hey.
Tell me.
- Marie. Marie.
- Marie.
It's okay. It's okay.
The Germans were rounding up
hostages off the street and...
She tried to escape.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
- Josef.
- Jan!
Stop. Stop. Josef, stop.
- Stop! Josef.
- It's my fault.
- Josef, it's not your fault.
Josef, listen to me!
- Listen to me.
- It's my fault.
Stop! Listen to me. Listen to me.
You're risking the lives of everyone.
For what? To shoot a few Germans?
She's gone. Josef, she's gone.
It's not your fault. Huh?
- It's my fault.
- It's not your fault.
- It's not your fault, Josef.
It's not your fault, okay.
I am sorry, Jan.
I'm sorry, Marie.
Mrs. Moravec, I'm sorry.
Hey.
Hey, it's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Father Petrek will meet you in there.
I'll send food with Ata. Go, go.
Thank you.
I regret nothing.
You are the bravest men I have ever met.
I'm Father Petrek. Welcome.
Please, come with me.
This is our hidden crypt.
You will be safe there.
Thank you, Father.
You made it.
Josef.
Gentlemen.
This is Švarc, Bublík and Hrubý.
They are from the airdrop this spring.
Boredom may be the biggest
enemy we have here.
I'm suggesting three men on guard duty
in the nave balcony at all times.
We rotate every six hours.
These three take first watch.
I'm sorry it wasn't the outcome
we all hoped for.
None more than us.
Reinhard Heydrich has died in hospital.
A direct result of the injuries
sustained in the attack.
Yesterday, the Germans
went to a village, Lidice,
and shot every man over the age of 16.
The women and children
have been taken to camps,
and the buildings
were razed to the ground.
There has been talk that the village
aided you somehow.
I've never even been to Lidice.
These are dangerous times.
Mere gossip wipes a whole village
from the face of the Earth.
Today Karl Frank issued
an amnesty broadcast.
A full pardon for any person
and their family
in exchange for any information
about the assassins,
even if they did not come forward before.
But there is a deadline of five days.
After that, they plan
to execute 30,000 Czechs.
- This must stop.
- What do you propose?
Me and Josef will go to a park,
place placards around our necks
saying that we killed Heydrich
and commit suicide.
- Jan.
- Stupid talk.
This is stupid talk.
As a soldier, it is your duty to
stay alive and continue fighting.
Do you understand that,
Warrant Officer Kubiš?
The responsibility does not rest with you.
We know who is responsible.
They will have to answer
eventually, and they will.
If I didn't believe that,
I would not be here now.
Thank you, Father.
Ata.
Have you seen Marie?
Is she well?
Beyond this brickwork and masonry,
there is a large main sewer
that empties into the river.
How do you know?
I found some plans
in Father Petrek's office.
Now, if we can chisel through this,
we have a means of escape.
Escape to where?
Well, until the British send plans
for our rescue, we are stuck here.
But should we be discovered,
there is no way out.
I would like us at least
to have this option.
We would then
take our chances in the streets.
Two men should be
working here at all times.
What's her name?
Lenka.
Earlier, what Jan said...
About taking your own lives.
Was he serious?
Maybe.
"Cowards die many times
before their deaths.
"The valiant never taste death but once."
Shakespeare.
You say you know the men who assassinated
Reichsprotektor Reinhard Heydrich,
but you didn't take part in it.
You say you don't know where they are,
but you know the family who sheltered them.
No, please... Please, no.
You walked in here on your own accord
to give us this statement.
You say you are a true patriot
and the reason for doing that
is because you want to protect your family
and for the killing
of innocent Czechs to stop.
And you say your name is...
Karel Curda.
Chalupský.
Ah!
Where are the parachutists?
I know nothing.
You must be confusing us
with other Moravecs.
Where are the parachutists?
Please, let me clean
myself up before I leave.
Go on, then.
My son is a violinist.
Tell them he knows
nothing of this. Please.
In the toilet.
Something triggered it.
Maybe other members
of the church found out.
Opálka. What did I miss?
Bishop Gorazd has talked to Father Petrek.
Apparently our presence here
is endangering the church.
He wants us to leave.
But Petrek has talked to Hajsky
and there is a plan to get us all out.
When?
Two in the coffins,
two under the dummy floors
and the other three
disguised as pall bearers.
That's the seven.
How soon can you be ready?
You like to play the violin.
Maybe you would like
to see your mother again.
Yes, we managed to save her.
No. No.
- No.
- We saved her head.
Where are the assassins?
Where are they hiding?
Please stop.
Where are the assassins?
Where are they hiding?
- Stop.
- Where are they?
They're in the church.
In the Cyril and Methodius Church.
The Germans are surrounding the church.
We have to warn the others.
No, no. There is no time.
Take up defensive positions.
We hold them from here.
Bublík, take the upper gallery.
Go back.
Back! Go back!
- The church is surrounded.
- We have to help them.
We must not give ourselves away, Josef.
- Jan!
- Hey!
- Keep quiet, please.
Block the stairwell.
That's our only way out.
It's also the only way up.
Bublík!
- I don't want to die.
- Bublík, look at me.
- Breathe.
Breathe with me. With me.
Big breath in. Big breath out.
I don't want to die today.
- I don't want to die today.
- As we were trained.
Here. Look.
Nice and easy. Nice and easy.
Concentrate on the detail. Come on.
- That's it.
- I'm sorry, Jan.
Okay?
Nice and easy.
Yeah.
We're all here with you.
And Czechoslovakia is here with us.
Cover the stairwell!
Bublík, the stairwell!
We've lost the stairwell!
Stairs!
I'm out!
Last one.
Bublík!
This is Jan Kubiš.
That's Adolf Opálka.
And him,
I don't know, but it's not
Josef Gabčík or Valčík.
Wait. Wait.
Hrubý, reload.
You should get your friends to surrender.
Josef?
You should surrender now
and save yourselves.
- There's Curda.
- Do you hear me?
- Curda!
You will be treated humanely
as prisoners of war.
We are Czechs.
We will never surrender!
Hey.
We save the last one...
For us.
We dig! We dig!
Keep digging! Don't stop!